Guide to the Office of Educational Research, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Office of Educational Research, Yale University, records
1922-1971
RU 571
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(4 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Office of Educational Research at Yale. Materials include correspondence concerning appointments, terminations and finances, Yale College faculty reports, reports done for the State of Connecticut, and College Entrance Examination Board files.
Yale University. Office of Educational Research
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-E (YRG 9-E), Records documenting Yale College offices, programs, and projects.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Office of Educational Research at Yale. Materials include correspondence concerning appointments, terminations and finances, Yale College faculty reports, reports done for the State of Connecticut, and College Entrance Examination Board files.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by type of material.
Education -- Research; Yale College (1887- ); Yale University -- Statistics; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Office of Educational Research
- Records, 1922-1971; Accession 1983-A-111
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research with the exception of appointments and terminations papers and budget materials located in box 5. Those are restricted until Jan 1, 2047 due to University policy set by the Yale Corporation.
  - Correspondence:, 1944-1971
    - A - M, Office files, 1944-1971 (Box 1)
    - N - Z, Office files, 1944-1971 (Box 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1954-1964 (Box 3)
  - Appointments and Terminations, 1963-1970 (Box 5)
    Appointments and terminations are restricted until Jan 1, 2047 due to university policy set by the Yale Corporation.
  - Budget Material, 1960-1968 (Box 5)
  - Office of Educational Research reports, 1957-1971 (Box 3)
  - Yale College faculty memoranda and reports, 1953-1970 (Box 3)
  - Reprints of A.B. Crawford, 1922-1947 (Box 3)
  - Reports done for the State of Connecticut, 1934-1939 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 3)
  - College Entrance Examination Board material and other papers (Box 4)